<!-- source: http://wikitravel.org/en/Lisbon -->
<data author="From Wikitravel" titleimage="Downtown_Lisbon.jpg"
    title="The Lisbon Experience: capital of monuments">
    <titleimage title="Downtown (Baixa)"/>
    <intro>The capital of Portugal, Lisbon has experienced a renaissance in recent years, with a
        contemporary culture that is alive and thriving and making its mark in today's Europe.
        Perched on the edge of the Atlantic Ocean, Lisbon is one of the rare Western European cities
        that faces the ocean and uses water as an element that defines the city. Lisbon enchants
        travelers with its white-bleached limestone buildings, intimate alleyways, and an easy-going
        charm that makes it a popular year-round destination. Lisbon enjoys a warm climate with mild
        winters and very warm summers.</intro>
    <images>
        <img
            caption="The Berardo Collection Museum is a museum that houses modern and contemporary art, together with modern, temporary exhibits. The permanent collection of the museum consist of the Berardo Collection"
            filename="CentroCulturaldeBelem.jpg" width="21" x="12" y="1" caption_x="25"/>
        <img
            caption="The Jerónimos Monastery replaced the church formerly existing in the same place, which was dedicated to Santa Maria de Belém and where the monks of the military-religious Order of Christ provided assistance to seafarers in transit. The harbour of Praia do Restelo was an advantageous spot for mariners, with a safe anchorage and protection from the winds, sought after by ships entering the mouth of the Tagus."
            filename="HieronymusKlosterSuedportal_Lisbon.jpg" width="10" x="23" y="26"
            caption_x="23"/>
    </images>
    <text>
        <par initial="T">he city stretches along the northern bank of the river Tejo as it flows
            into the Atlantic Ocean. As the terrain rises north away from the water, steep streets
            and stairways form the old tangled districts or give way to green parks in the western
            suburbs.</par>
        <par title="Getting there">In general, if you are arriving by plane in Lisbon and it is
            still day time, it is almost always better to use public transport - buses or the metro
            system - to your hotel or final destination. The airport information desk at Lisbon
            airport can provide you with all the required information. Taxi drivers at the taxi
            stand at Lisbon are infamous for their dishonesty and unreliability and if they can rip
            you off, they will. If you do not speak Portuguese or if you don't know the shortest way
            to your destination, avoid using a taxi unless there is no other option. If your final
            destination is less than 1 mile from the airport, taxi drivers will refuse to take you
            although they are not allowed to refuse destinations. If you are not carrying too much
            luggage and it is not late in the night, you are better off simply getting a bus or the
            metro to city center.</par>
        <par title="Tram 28">Instead of paying for a ride on one of the costly tourist trams, try
            Tram 28. Tram (or "Eléctrico" in the Portuguese) Line 28 is one of only three
            traditional tram lines that still operate in Lisbon. These trams, which until the
            late-1980's ran all through-out Lisbon, were manufactured between 1936 and 1947. Tram 28
            winds its way through the "Old Town" of Lisbon (dating from the 17th century) beginning
            in Graça then down to the Alfama and to the Baixa then up through Chiado to Bairro Alto
            and then down to Campo Ourique, taking you by many of Lisbon's most famous and
            interesting sites including monuments, churches and gardens. The trip is hilly, noisy
            and hectic but it affords many beautiful glimpses of the city. And, although the tram
            can sometimes be overrun with tourists, you will definitely get a flavour of the locals,
            as many "Lisboetas" commute daily on these historical trams. Tickets cost €1.05 if paid
            by "Viva Viagem" card and €2.85 if purchased on-board or at a vending machine (note that
            these machines do not accept notes, and are sometime even out of change, so make sure
            you have the correct change!). From start  to finish the ride takes around 30 minutes.</par>
    </text>
</data>
